===时间轴校正&双语合并&压制-刘文举===
My QQ number : 672832932
My 51 blog:http://shuifeng880621.51.com
===时间轴校正&双语合并&压制-刘文举===
Hunan University of Science and Technology
January 10 . 2010
齐贝!
Zeebad!
只是场恶梦
Only a bad dream.
一切似乎正常
Everything seems fine.
"哦,是魔法"
"Oh, ho, ho, it's magic"
"你知道"
"You know"
"别相信不是如此"
"Never believe it's not so"
"是魔法"
"It's magic"
"你知道"
"You know"
"别相信不是如此"
"Never believe it's not so"
"未曾清醒过"
"Never been awake"
"未曾看过破晓"
"Never seen a day break"
"晨间倚靠在枕头上"
"Leaning on my pillow in the morning"
"懒洋洋地躺在床上"
"Lazy day in bed"
"音乐在脑海中浮现"
"Music in my head"
"晨光中播送着疯狂音乐"
"Crazy music playing,in the morning light"
"哦,是魔法"
"Oh, ho, ho, it's magic"
"你知道"
"You know"
"别相信不是如此"
"Never believe it's not so"
"是魔法"
"It's magic"
"你知道"
"You know"
"别相信不是如此"
"Never believe it's not so"
"我爱晴天"
"I love my sunny day"
"遥远的梦"
"Dream of far away"
"枕边入梦"
"Dreaming on my pillow"
"在清晨中"
"In the morning"
"未曾清醒过"
"Never been awake"
"未曾见过破晓"
"Never seen a day break"
"倚靠在枕头上"
"Leaning on my pillow"
"在晨光中"
"In the morning light"
要迟到了!
Oh!we will be late!
...大家稍待一会
...a lot more of you later.
别现在,拜
Not just now, please.
嘟狗!
Dougal!
嘟狗,我就知道你会赶来
Dougal, I knew you'd make it.
你刚好及时赶上音乐会!
You're just in time for the concert!
对,佛罗伦丝,当然了我不会错过的
Yes, Florence, of course.I wouldn't miss it for the world.
别以为你只要现身就可以得到糖块
Well, don't think you're getting a sugar lump just for turning up.
糖? 谁需要糖呀?
Sugar? Who needs sugar?
绝不是我,我戒了! 今天早上!
Not me. I quit! This morning!
我亲眼看到才相信!
Hm, I'll believe that when I see it!
爱蜜楚准备开始了
-# Toreador Song from Carmen
- Ermintrude's about to begin.
-哦,不!-勇敢点!
- Oh, no!- Be brave!
-佛罗伦丝...-嘘!
- Florence...- Ssh!
"女孩,你真的令我心动"
Girl, you really got me goin'
"你令我心动,所以我不知道
我不知道我在做什么"
You got me so I don't know,what I'm doin'
"是的,你真的令我心动"
Yeah, you really got me now
"你令我心动,教我夜里辗转难眠"
You got me so I can't sleep at night
加油,宝贝!
Go baby!
"是的,你真的令我心动"
Ye-e-e-e-eah.Yeah, you really got me now
"你令我心动,所以我...
我不知道我在做什么"
You got me so I...I don't know what I'm doing
"是的,你真的令我心动"
Oh, yeah, you really got me now- Mm?
"你令我心动,教我夜里辗转难眠"
You got me so I can't sleep at night
"你真的令我心动,你真的令我心动"
You really got me, you really got me
"你真的令我心动"
You really got me
"你懂我的意思吗?"
D'you know what I mean?
"瞧,千万别放我自由"
See, don't ever set me free
"我一直想依偎在你身边"
I always wanna be by your side,La-la-la la la la
"女孩,你真的令我心动"
Girl, you really got me now
"你令我心动,教我夜里辗转难眠"
You've got me so.I can't sleep at night
唱出来
Take it out.
"你真的令我心动"
Yeah.You really got me now
"你令我心动
所以我不知道我在做什么"
You got me so I don't know.what I'm doin'
"是的,你真的令我心动"
Oh, yeah, you really got me now
"你令我心动,教我夜里辗转难眠"
You got me so I can't sleep at night
"你真的令我心动"
"是的,你真的令我心动"
You really got me.Yeah, yeah, you really got me
"你真的令我心动
你知道你好像真的令我心动"
You really got me,you know, you, like, really got me
跟上我的拍子,爱蜜楚!
Groove me, Erminduda!
"你真的令我心动,你真的令我心动"
You really got me, you really got me
"你真的令我心动"
-嗯,宝贝
You really got me- Yeah, baby
"你真的令我心动"
-使出吃奶之力吧,妈咪!
You really got me- Milk it, Mummy!
"动...!"
Me-e-e-e-e-e-e!
惨惨惨
Oh dear, oh dear, oh dear.
真是突如其来的意外那可不容易修补呢
What an unforeseeable accident.That's not an easy fix, that.
看情形破损的太严重了
We're looking at
a multiple abrasion friction gash.
我还不知道你是个合格技工呢,嘟狗
I did not know you were a qualified mechanic, Dougal.
当然! 如果你给我打气机,黏胶,四颗西瓜
Of course! If you bring me an air pump,
some glue,4 watermelons,
滑水板,一把伸缩喇叭和口香糖
water skis, a trombone and gobstoppers
我或许就能帮你了
I might just be able to help you out.
哈哈! 算我好运碰上你
Ha, ha! I am lucky you were here.
-帮我顾下东西好吗?-我会顾好的,没问题
- Will you take care of my things?
- Oh, I'll take care of them, all right.
我想我会先照顾那些棒棒糖
I think I'll take care of
those lollipops first.
然后是那冰冻果子露再来是那焦糖牛乳糖
Then...ooh, those sherbets.And...ooh, those caramel creams.
哇!
Whoa!
Whoooa!
谢谢,谢谢
Thank you. Thank you.
安可! 安可!
Encore! Encore!
谢谢,真甜蜜
Thank you. So sweet.
-现在,为了我下一场,我应该...-哇!
- Now, for my next number, I shall...- Whoa!
救命呀!
Help!
哦,嘟狗!
Oh, Dougal!
救命! 救我下去!
Help! Get me off!
这东西怎么停啊?
How do I stop this thing?
拜救救我!
Please help me!
他每次进场总是轰动全场
He's always got to make
a big entrance.
老天,情形不太妙
Oh dear, that's not good.
-孩子们抓紧-救命!
- Hold on tight, children.- Help!
洛斯提先生!
Mr Rusty!
快! 我下不去!
Quick! I can't get off!
我的天啊,失控了!
Oh, my goodness, it's out of control!
怎...怎么了?
Wh-What's happening?
真是教华格纳哑口无言!
This is too Wagnerian for words!
哦,佛罗伦丝!
Oh, Florence!
-那是怎么搞的?-糟糕之旅!
- What was that?- Bad trip!
普契尼保佑我们!旋转木马是怎么回事?
Puccini preserve us!What's happened to the Roundabout?
哦,不,怎么回事?
Ugh! Oh, no. What's happening?
佛罗伦丝! 你没事吧?
Florence! Are you all right?
嘟狗! 好冷!
Dougal! I'm cold!
别担心,佛罗伦丝我们会救你出来的
Don't worry, Florence.We'll get you out of there.
我们到底该怎么办?
What on earth shall we do?
齐比迪! 齐比迪! 齐比迪!
Zebedee! Zebedee! Zebedee!
齐比迪,谢天谢地
Zebedee, thank goodness.
怎么了,我的朋友们?
Whatever's the matter, my friends?
-发生了可怕的事-你看
- Something awful has happened.- Look.
哦,不!
Oh, no!
我一直希望这一天不会到来
I hoped this day would never come.
怎么,星期二吗?
What, Tuesdays?
可是星期二很棒呀!
But Tuesdays are great!
-每逢星期二我们烤蛋糕...-嘟狗,不是
- On Tuesdays we make cake..- No Dougal.
是齐贝逃脱的这一天!
The day Zeebad escapes!
齐贝?我以为那只是个长毛狗故事
Zeebad? I thought that was just a shaggy dog story.
恐怕不是,嘟狗他是千真万确存在的
I'm afraid not, Dougal. He's all too real.
铁石心肠,残暴无道
Cold-hearted,tyrannous and cruel.
曾将我们的世界封在冰雪中数千年
For thousands of years,he kept our world bound in ice.
如今你释放他,他可再自由发挥他的恶势力
And now you've released him, he's free to wield his terrifying power once more.
终于自由了!
Free at last!
花了一万年
It took 10,000 years,
不过最棒的事物是值得等待的
but the best things are worth waiting for.
力量,复仇...
Power. Revenge...
还有...更多的力量!
and, er...more power!
冷,但还不够冷到我高兴
Cold.But not cold enough for my liking.
哈哈!
Ha, ha!
不久之后,到处就会一片冰天雪地了
Soon it will be.nice and frozen everywhere,
就像齐比迪破坏掉一切之前那样子
just like it was before Zebedee ruined everything.
现在,从哪开始呢?
Now, where to begin?
这是什么?
What's this?
正是我需要的...一个心腹!
Ooh, just what I need - a henchman!
今日一个士兵,明日征服全世界!
Today one soldier, tomorrow the world!
然后也许,再多三个士兵!
And then, perhaps,three more soldiers!
专心,齐贝,专心点!
Focus, Zeebad, focus!
成功了!
I've done it!
一忠实,坏的格斗机器会服从我每个命令!
A lean, mean, fighting machine,who'll obey my every command!
向右看!
Eyes right!
齐步走!
Quick march!
"他是个忠实,坏心眼的格斗机器"
He's a lean, mean, fighting machine
"真正的坏蛋,懂我意思吧?"
The real deal, know what I mean?
"往前迈进"
Marching along
"他会和你一决胜负"
Well, he'll take you on
"小心,他来了"
Watch out, here he comes
"他是个格斗机器"
He's a fighting machine
立正!
Attention!
报名
Name?
中士山姆,皇家第一发条团!
Sergeant Sam, First Decorative Clockwork Regiment, saaaaah!
很好! 从现起,你任务就是帮我找回三颗钻石
Good! From now on, your mission is to help me recover 3 diamonds
被个奸诈小偷从我身上偷走的
taken from me by a treacherous thief.
路途会很艰辛
Mm. The road will be hard.
痛苦、悲惨和磨难将不断与你为伍
Pain, misery and torment will be your constant companion,
而你唯一的解脱将是死亡!
and your only release will be death!
可以要求放假吗?
Oh. Er, can I ask about holidays?
-夏天放假三周-非常慷慨,长官
- Three weeks in summer.- Very generous, sir.
不过不会再有夏天了!
Not that it will ever be summer again!
现在来看看那个臭虫齐比迪想搞什么鬼
Now let's see what that worm Zebedee is up to.
他有几位小朋友呢
Well, well.He's got some little friends, has he?
我很快会去拜访他们
I'll soon see to them.
到我的旧窝!我们计划来个一连串的攻击
To my old lair!We shall plan our line of attack.
唯有找回魔法钻石
Only by returning the enchanted diamonds
放回旋转木马原来的位置才能打败齐贝
to their original places on the Roundabout will you defeat Zeebad.
但如果被他先发现他会用它们来冰冻太阳!
But if he finds them first,he'll use them to freeze the sun!
寸土寸草不生
Nothing will grow. Not even grass.
好的,各位,我们有个问题
OK, people. We've got a problem.
其中一颗钻石就藏在这儿的旋转木马
One of the diamonds is hidden here,on the Roundabout.
我必须留在后面来守护它
I must stay behind to guard it.
要找出其它两颗你们会需要这份地图
To find the other two,you will need this map.
你们必须前往北边山上
You must head north into the mountains.
没时间好磨蹭了
There is no time to waste.
希望你有提供我们适合的交通工具
Well, I hope you've supplied us with an appropriate mode of transportation.
哈哈,我倒车一下
Whoops! Ha, ha, I'll just back up.
勉强算是东方快车,亲爱的!
It's hardly the Orient Express, darling!
它有头等舱吗?
Does it have first class?
什么?
What?
谨慎保管这个小小魔法盒
Take good care of this little box of tricks.
紧要关头时可能会救你们一命
It may save you in your hour of need.
佛罗伦丝,撑下去,我会回来的
Florence, hold on. I'll be back.
-我保证
-别太久唷
- I promise.- Don't be too long.
不管发生什么事
千万别怪你自己
Whatever happens,you mustn't blame yourself.
不,交给我们吧
- No, leave that to us.- Hm!
所有人登车!
All aboard!
孩子们别担心我们的朋友会救我们的
Don't worry, children.Our friends will save us.
蒸汽正常,锅炉室正常活塞正常!
Steam, check. Furnace, check.Pistons, check. Wahey!
乘客抱歉,忘了还有乘客
Sorry. Passengers.I forgot the passengers.
树木好!
Hello, trees!
小鸟好!
Hello, birds!
恐怖凛冽的雾气好
Hello, scary freezing mist.
幸亏它们没听到
Oh, dear. Lucky they can't hear me.
我不希望它们认为
我是辆恐怖列车
I wouldn't want them thinking I'm a scaredy-train.
哦,佛罗伦丝
Oh, Florence.
不知我们去何方,不知他们知不知道
I wonder where we're going.I wonder if they even know.
不知道他们知不知道我根本不知道,哦,这太刺激了!
I wonder if they know that I don't even know. Oh, this is exciting!
-嘟狗-干嘛?
- Dougal.- Yeah?
千万不要觉得内疚,只因为这全是你的错
You mustn't feel guilty just because it's all your fault.
-我?-不好意思,那样说不太好
- Me?- Oh, sorry, that didn't come out right.
我的错?
My fault?
我做了什么?
What did I do?
除了毁掉旋转木马...
What, apart from wrecking the Roundabout,
困住佛罗伦丝和孩子们...
trapping Florence and the children
还导致一个企图冰冻太阳的疯子脱逃
and causing the escape of a maniac intent on freezing the sun?
我只是想牙缝塞点糖果
I only wanted to get my teeth into some sweeties.
对,就是糖果起的因也许是冰面包
Yeah, it starts with some sweets, man,maybe an iced bun,
在你察觉之前你就已经一天吃了两包
and before you know it,you're on two bags a day.
我晓得,我有过经验
I know man, I've been there.
也许你有个问题我的毛茸茸朋友?
Maybe you've got, like, a problem,my furry friend?
我没有! 我不会放弃的直到我尽我一切力量...
I have not! And I'll not rest until I've done everything in my power
把事情烤好
to bake things right.
我是指把事情搞好
I mean make things right.
老天,越来越冷了
Goodness, it's getting cold.
告诉我一下在这里我螺栓螺帽都要冻僵了!
Tell me about it.I'm freezing my nuts and bolts off here!
我必须说,你们全做的很棒
I must say,you're all doing a wonderful job.
继续保持下去
Keep up the good work.
晚餐吃什么? 我饿扁了!
What's for dinner anyway?I'm famished!
我懂了,沉默以待,是不是?
哼!
Oh, I see, the silent treatment is it?Huh!
幸好我带了些秘密补给!
It's lucky I brought some secret supplies. Mm!
满月
Ah, full moon.
听说满月教人陷入罗曼蒂克气氛中
They say the full moon puts people in the mood for romance.
多么完美的场地呀,刚适合办户外韦瓦第节庆演唱
What a perfect venue for an open-air Verdi festival.
这里会挤的人山人海的
People would flock here.
就连羊也受不了那种噪音
Not even sheep
would flock to that noise.
惨了
- Uh-oh.- Mm?
真是九死一生
That was a close shave.
我的口香糖! 哦,不!
My gobstoppers! Oh, no!
只剩一个了!
There's only one left!
对! 我们都该好好睡个美容觉了
Right! It's time we all got some beauty sleep.
狄伦?
Dylan?
狄伦!
Dylan!
-怎...怎么?-睡觉时间到了!
- Wha... What?- Bedtime!
老天,谢谢你叫醒我让我晓得
Gee, thanks for waking me up to let me know.
应该要有人来守卫
Someone should keep watch.
-我在想...-真是太感谢你了
- I was thinking...- Good of you to offer.
-什么?-晚安
- What?- Good night.
-晚安,各位亲爱的-晚安安,爱蜜楚
- Good night, darlings.- Night-night, Ermindude.
什么?
Eh? What?
现在我是沉睡的列车了
Now my impression of a sleeper train.
等等,等等...
Wait, wait...
糟糕,我牙膏用完了!
Oh, no. I've run out of toothpaste!
我干嘛非得当守卫犬?
Why do I have to be the guard dog?
不能是守卫蜗牛或守卫母牛或...?
What's wrong with a guard snail or a guard cow or...?
谁在那里?
Who goes there?
是敌是友? 还是...
Friend or foe? Or...
糜鹿? 感觉有点忧郁(蓝色)?
...moose? F-Feeling a bit blue?
你不是唯一这样的
You're not the only one.
是你朋友吗?
Oh, is this a friend of yours?
我想这代表不是吧!
I'll take that as a no!
-嘟狗?-嘟嘟狗?
- Dougal?- Dougie?
-嘟狗?-嘟狗?
- Dougal?- Dougal?
-嘟狗?-小嘟? 小嘟?
- Dougal?- Doogie? Doogie, man?
出来,嘟狗! 出来,嘟狗!
Here, Dougal. Here, Dougal.
我发现个痕迹.也许会指引我们找到他
Oooh, I've found a trail.Maybe it'll lead us to him.
或者也许会指引我们找到...
Or maybe it'll lead us to that...
糜鹿
...moose.
我觉得他想告诉我们什么事
I think he's trying to tell us something.
你有见过我们朋友嘟狗吗?
Have you seen our friend Dougal?
又大又黑的鼻子,脚上的毛一团乱糟糟的
Big black nose,looks like a bad hair day on legs?
你在浪费时间,布莱恩
You're wasting your time, Brian.
谁听过会讲话的糜鹿呢?
Whoever heard of a talking moose?
该说是唱歌剧的母牛吧
Says the opera-singing cow.
听着,我觉得他想要我们跟他走
Look, I think he wants us to follow him.
快点! 用最快速度前进吧!
Come on! As fast as you can!
现在,你这低等智慧的毛刷
通通老实招来
Now, you dim-witted draft excluder,tell me everything.
我是只非常快乐的小狗
Well, I was a very happy puppy.
我最初的印象便是和佛罗伦丝接网球
My first memories are of catching tennis balls with Florence.
-后来我长大了,她...-不,你这进化迟钝的怪胎!
- Then, as I grew up, she...- No, you follicly-enhanced freak!
告诉我钻石的事
Tell me about the diamonds,
否则我教你求生不得求死不能!
or I'll make you wish you'd packed a pooper-scooper!
我? 我什么都不知道甚至连地图都没有
Me? I don't know anything.I don't even have the map.
原来有地图啊
So, there's a map, eh?
不不不不...没有地图
No, no, no, no... No map.
他们当然不会放心交给你携带
Well, of course they wouldn't trust you with it.
你只是只小笨狗
You're just a silly little dog.
你可能会埋起来或嚼了它!
You'd probably bury it or chew it!
地图在谁身上?
So, who does have the map?
我绝不会说的!
- Eh?- I'll never tell!
不会吗?
Oh, no?
山姆,别再拿着那根掸子刷来刷去的了
Sam, stop mincing around with that duster.
给他严刑逼供直到他全盘托出为止
Torture this boarding house for fleas until he tells us everything.
是,长官!
Yes, sir!
那好吧,酷刑!
Right, then. Torture!
听着,这种事我还不大熟
所以...
Look, this is all a bit new to me,so, erm...
你最怕的是什么?
what is it you're most afraid of?
不久就可以恢复我全部的实力了
It won't be long now until I have my full powers back.
然后我...
Then I...
不! 不,不! 不要那样!
Oh, no! No, no! Not that!
很好,山姆!
Good Sam!
好好玩吧!
Enjoy yourself!
拜不要! 别再来了!
No, please! Ooh, no more!
-26...
-哦,我受不了了!
- 26...- Ooh, I can't stand it!
27...他不可能吃下更多了!
27... He can't possibly take much more of this!
你已吃了27个方糖!
You've eaten 27 sugar cubes!
你得逼我吃下一百个
我才会告诉你一切!
You'll have to make me eat 100 before I tell you anything!
不,不! 拜!
No, no! Please!
钻石很快就会是我的了
Soon the diamonds will be mine
而我就能把这丑陋的绿色星球...
and I'll be able to turn this hideous green planet
变成一处可爱的冰冻荒地
into a lovely frozen wasteland.
太可怕了!
This is terrible!
-不,你千万不可!
-再来一点
- No, you mustn't!- Little more.
-...你不动手了吗?
-还要多久? 我在工作...
-...don't you?- How long will this take? I'm working...
喔! 你在害死我!
- Eh?- Ooh, Ow! You're killing me!
听起来蛮痛的!
- Argh!- Ooh, that sounded painful!
嘻嘻! 干的漂亮,山姆
Hee, hee! Excellent work, Sam.
不! 少碰我,你这邪恶的恶魔!
No! Leave me alone, you evil fiend!
你在碎碎个什么劲?
What are you talking about?
是我啊...爱蜜楚
It's me - Ermintrude.
你能五分钟后再来吗?
我才刚开始玩的开心呢
Could you come back in five minutes?I was just starting to enjoy myself.
快点,嘟狗
Oh, come on, Dougal.
蒸汽全开向后!
Full steam backwards!
解决掉他,山姆
Finish him off, Sam.
我们该...
It's time we...
狗!
你对他做了什么好事,你这白痴?
The dog! What have you done with him, you idiot?
长官,我被一头飞天母牛给压扁了!
Ooh... Well, sir, I got flattened by a flying cow. Oooh!
别跑的这么快!
Not so fast!
放开我的尾巴,畜生
Ow! Ooh, let go of my tail,you br-brute.
爱蜜楚!
Ermintrude!
再快一点!
Faster!
倒车,倒车!
Back it up, back it up!
你真好心来拜访我
How nice of you to drop in.
拉!
Pull!
很抱歉,无法久留了
Sorry, can't stay long.
极速飞车!
- Aaaagh!- Uh-oh! Whiplash!
你好
Hello.
她从这个角度看比较好看
Ah, she looks a lot better from this angle.
等她成为座上佳肴时会更好看
She'll look a lot better when she's being served with a side order of fries.
去追他们!
After them!
这里又冷又不舒服
我们在哪里?
This is cold and very unpleasant. Where are we?
-继续走! 继续走!
-一定有别条路的
- Keep going! Keep going!- There must be another way.
对,对
Yeah, man. Yeah, yeah.
继续走,各位
Keep going, people.
我是火车,不是雪橇!
I'm a train, not a snowboard!
"吧-吧-吧碰"
Ba-ba-ba bom
"继续转呀转"
Keep spinnin', spinnin' around
"吧-吧-吧碰"
Ba-ba-ba bom
"继续转呀转"
Keep spinnin', spinnin' around
"吧-吧-吧碰"
Ba-ba-ba bom
"继续转呀转"
Keep spinnin', spinnin' around
"吧-吧-吧碰"
Ba-ba-ba bom
"继续转呀转"
Keep spinnin', spinnin' around
"啊"
A-a-a-ah
"吧-吧-吧碰"
Ba-ba-ba bom
我的用途是行驶...不是滑雪!
I was made to shunt...not to ski!
哇,好深
Whoa, man, that's deep.
我们我们已抵达了尽头
I think we've reached the end of the line.
相信我所说的话吧
You took the words right out of my mouth.
山姆,拔剑!
Sam, your sword!
长官! 冲锋!
Sir! En garde!
喂,老兄,给和平一个机会
Hey, man, give peace a chance.
现在神仙也救不了你们了
Nobody can save you now.
齐比迪! 齐比迪! 齐比迪!
Zebedee! Zededee! Zebedeeeee!
是你!
You!
我们又见面了
So we meet again.
没错
Indeed.
我等了一万年要报仇
I've waited 10,000 year for my revenge.
诚如你所知道的
复仇这道菜,越冷越够味
And, as you know,revenge is a dish best served cold.
有些人喜欢热食,齐贝!
Some like it hot, Zeebad!
我底下还有些弹簧呢,齐贝
I've still got some spring in my step,Zeebad.
漂亮,齐比迪!
Well done, Zebedee!
-哦,不
-我想弹簧已经弹掉了
- Oh, no.- I think the spring has sprung.
喂! 你们想去哪呀?
Oi! Where do you think you lot are going?
山姆?
Sam?
山姆! 住手!
考虑清楚你在干嘛
Sam! Stop!Think about what you're doing.
我的任务不是考虑
It's not my job to think.
我是士兵,就遵守命令呀
I'm a soldier. I'm just following orders.
你或许穿着军服,山姆但心里面想的才重要
You may wear a soldier's uniform,Sam, but it's what's inside that counts.
小心!
Look out!
哎呀
Blimey.
逃! 快逃!
Run! Run!
大伙快点,我们的机会来了
Come on, gang, here's our chance.
小胡子让开!喔,差点变牙签了
Move that moustache!Oops, nearly a toothpick.
你在阳光下的日子结束了齐比迪,你这心软的弹簧!
Your days in the sun are over,Zebedee, you benevolent bed spring!
现在该轮到齐贝的时代了!
Now it's time for Zeebad!
停! 齐比迪有麻烦了!
Stop! Zebedee's in trouble!
不,救你们自己吧!
No, save yourselves!
怎么办? 怎么办?
What shall we do? What shall we do?
我们不能丢下他不官救他!
Well, we can't leave him.To the rescue!
你们得去找钻石!
You've got to find the diamonds!
结束了
Ah, so it ends.
我的仇人终于永远消失了
My nemesis finally vanquished forever.
去取得钻石!
Get the diamonds!
不!
Noooooo!
没得选择了,现在一定要离开
We have no choice.We must leave now.
这里我们再也帮不上忙了
There's nothing more we can do here.
-快点,嘟狗-快
- Come on, Doog.- Quick.
掉一滴泪差不多就够了
It's almost enough to make one weep,
若非我这么非常非常快乐的话哈哈!
if only I wasn't so very, very happy.Ha, ha!
现在什么也阻挡不了我了!
Now nothing can stand in my way!
不对,山姆
要从喉咙后面发出来
No, Sam.It's all in the back of the throat.
此时就算我能说话也不晓得该说什么了
Right now, even if I could speak,I wouldn't know what to say.
不敢相信他竟然真的走了
I can't believe he's really gone.
齐比死了,宝贝,齐比死了
Zeb's dead, baby. Zeb's dead.
现在谁来救佛罗伦丝和孩子们呢?
And now who's going to help Florence and the children?
谁会帮助我们?
Who's going to help us?
坚强点,爱蜜楚
Be strong, Ermintrude.
我们必须勇敢起来找到钻石
We have to be brave and find the diamonds.
毕竟那是齐比迪的临终愿望
After all,
that was Zebedee's dying wish.
情形不妙,老兄
It's no good, man.
少了齐比迪,我们一无是处
Without Zebedee, we're nothing.
不,布莱恩说的对
No, Brian's right.
我们要拯救我们的世界
We're gonna save our world.
地图在哪?
Now where's the map?
那边! 朝向那边最高峰
There! Head for the tallest mountain
in that range.
就是那股精神,布莱恩!
That's the spirit, Brian!
现在上刀山下油锅也阻止不了我取得钻石的决心
Nothing short of a sea of boiling lava will keep me from that diamond now.
哦,蜜糖
Oh, sugar.
钻石就在那里
Well, that's where the diamond is.
谁去拿?
Who's going to get it?
钻石是女孩最好的朋友快过去吧,爱蜜楚
Ah, well, diamonds are a girl's best friend. Off you trot, Ermintrude.
钻石应该由男士交给淑女而不是反过来才对
Men are supposed to give ladies diamonds. Not the other way round.
嘿,我以为狗狗才该去接取的
Hey, I thought dogs
were supposed to fetch.
我的优点一向是“坐下,嘟狗”以及“待着,嘟狗,待着”
My forte's always been "sit, Dougal".That, and "Stay, Dougal, stay".
狄伦...你这么勇敢的兔子一定只要稍微跳一下就过去了
Dylan...surely it's only a short hop for such a brave bunny.
对个呆兔子来说比较像是一落千丈
More like a long drop for a dumb rabbit.
安静!
Quiet!
那边有座桥
Ahem. There's a bridge over there.
我想我应该在这里警戒你们过桥到另一边...
I think I ought to keep a lookout here
while you lot cross to the other s...
他不是狗,是胆小鬼
He's not a dog, he's a chicken.
好吧好吧,我懂
All right, all right. I understand.
没我带队你们不肯去
You don't want to go
without your leader.
少往自己脸上贴金了
Talk about wag your own tail.
哦,我惧高
Oooh, I'm scared of heights.
别担忧高度...你要担忧的是宽度才对
Don't worry about them -it's the widths you have to worry about.
这事轻而易举
This is gonna be easy.
-小心点!-很容易嘛
- Careful!- Easy does it.
-离边边只差一点点-别往下看就是
- A bit close to the edge.- Just don't look down.
笔直看着前方
Look straight ahead.
哦,滚烫的岩浆,老天!
Ooh, hot rocks, man!
眼睛看着路面!
Keep your eyes on the road!
-什...什么路面?-没问题的,别担心
- Wha... What road, man?- I'm on it. Don't worry.
干嘛停下来?
Why have you stopped?
一次一步
One step at a time.
哦,没错,哦...
Oh, yeah, oh...
前进了,这会很容易的
There we go. This is gonna be easy.
不!
Noooo!
狄伦! 想想办法!
Dylan! Do something!
你们就不能一个跳出去推吗?
Can't one of you
just hop out and push?
我完全没受过火车训练
Whoa. I'm totally not train trained.
那样说根本没帮助,狄伦!
That's not helping, Dylan!
加上一段铁轨和一罐热油
Ah, for a nice siding
and a can of warm oil.
无须惊慌
No need to panic.
现在才该惊慌
Now. Now is a good time to panic.
摇滚,老天!
Rock and roll, man!
棒极了
Brilliant.
我受够了大众传输工具!
I've had it with public transport!
钻石!
The diamond!
就在那里!
And there you have it!
我已带领各位找到了第一颗钻石!
- I have led you all to the first diamond!
- Wow!
狄伦,头彩就让给你,好吗?
Dylan, do the honours, would you?
嗯,酷
Yeah. Cool.
我想这东西需要调整
Er, I-I think this thing needs tuning.
有事要发生了!
Something's happening!
-我的脚冻僵了-我好冷
- My feet are frozen.- I'm cold.
加油,孩子们我们...我们必须勇敢才行
Come on, children.We... We have to be brave.
看! 是佛罗伦丝!
Look! It's Florence!
奇怪,刚才我以为听到了...
Strange. For a second there,
I thought I heard...
哦...我一定是快疯了
Oh... I must be going mad.
她能听见我! 佛罗伦丝!
She can hear me! Florence!
是我嘟狗呀,我来救你了!
It's me, Dougal. I've come to save you!
嘟狗? 是你吗?
Dougal? Is that you?
-怎么? 不!
-嘟狗?
- What? No!- Dougal?
-她逐渐消失了!
-嘟狗!
- She's fading!- Dougal!
才一天光景
且孩子们迅速结冻中
It's only been one day and the children are freezing fast.
担忧你们的朋友吗?
哈哈哈!
Concerned for your friends?Ha, ha, ha!
我也要拿走地图,请
And I'll take the map too, please.
等等,你怎会知道有...
Wait, how do you know there's a...
他们逼供成招的!
Well, they tortured it out of me!
地图给我!
Give me that map!
-请!
-等我死掉再说!
- Please!- Over my dead body!
山姆,拿出大蒜奶油来!
Sam, get out the garlic butter!
我觉得有点儿嘴馋
I'm feeling a little peckish.
你吹牛
You're bluffing.
试试看呀,你这无骨的粘液!
Try me, you spineless slime-spreader!
少惹他!
Leave him alone!
地图拿去吧
Take the map.
你真是卑鄙的恶魔!
You're a despicable fiend!
我知道,哈哈哈
那是天生的,真的
I know, ha, ha, ha. It's a gift, really.
同情是天大的弱点
Compassion is such a weakness.
抱歉我们无法留下来
不过你们知道情形的
Sorry we can't stay but you know how it is.
一统万民,冰冻天下
- People to rule, places to freeze.- Hup, hup, hup!
快点,智障
我们得毁掉这座桥!
Come on, imbecile,we have to destroy the bridge!
再见了,废物们!
So long, suckers!
等一下
Hold up.
干的好,士兵!
Good work, soldier!
孺子可教也
There's hope for you yet.
谢谢你,长官!
Thank you, sir!
好险!
Cor!
老天,他们不像以前那样
铺设碎石子步道
Man, they don't make crumbling rock causeways like they used to.
还有机会...像是长回来吗?
Is there any chance it will, like, grow back?
至少我们平安且暖和
At least we'll be nice and warm.
悲剧啊! 我们死定了!
Oh, tragedy! We're doomed!
我才正要大大扬名呢
And just as I was about to make it big.
-你是很大呀
-谢了,嘟狗
- You are big.- Thank you, Dougal.
但我希望我的事业高峰
不会到这火山峰为止
But I was hoping the peak of a volcano wouldn't be the pinnacle of my career.
大伙冷静点
我藏了样东西可能有帮助
Chill out, guys. I've got something stashed that just might help.
狄伦,我们没空用娱乐活动来实验
Dylan, we don't have time to experiment with recreational activities.
齐比迪的魔法盒!
Zebedee's Magic Box!
当然!
Of course!
现在,只要我能弄懂
怎样操作这个东西
Now, if I could just get my head round how to work this thing.
齐比迪有给谁说明书吗?
Did Zebedee give anyone the instructions?
按下按钮就是!
Just press the button!
一艘船,好极了
A boat. Brilliant.
从这儿上船将会一帆风顺
It'll be plain sailing from here on in.
等一下! 我想到了
Wait! I've got it.
搭帐篷!
The tents!
他这回真的疯了
He's really lost it this time.
这种高温会令我的牛角弯曲!
Oh, this heat is making my horns curl!
我样子一定很难看
I must look a sight.
不,爱蜜楚,我认为你的样子...
Oh, no, Ermintrude. I think you look...
是这样子,我觉得你...
That is, I find you...
看起来...
Look...
万一我们无法逃离这里
我只想让你知道...
in case we don't make it out of here,I just want you to know that...
全体登船!
All aboard!
这太神奇了!
我以前从没到过这么高
This is amazing!I've never been this high before.
事实上,我以前从没离开过地面
我们在做什么呀?
In fact, I've never been off the groundbefore. What are we doing?
干的好,狄伦,用气球脱逃
Well done, Dylan. A balloon escape.
老天! 你真聪明
My! You are clever.
是在于高度重于态度,爱蜜楚
It's all about altitude over attitude,Ermindude.
抱歉一下,不过还是有个小小问题
Excuse me,but there's still one small problem.
我们不知道要往哪去
We have no idea where we're going.
布莱恩说的对
我们可能会飘浮好几年!
Brian's right.We could drift around for years!
或者我们可以跟在他们后头
Or we could just, like, follow them.
再快一点,山姆
你划的像个挤奶工人!
Faster, Sam. You row like a milkmaid!
别紧张,长官
Ease up, sir.
现在那些惹人厌的小偷
已经不碍事了,何必急呢?
Now those pesky thieves are out the way, what's the big rush?
山姆,想像一下
如果你等了一万年
Sam, imagine if you'd waited 10,000 years
回到你冰冻王国的家乡
to come home to your frozen kingdom,
结果却发现世界遍布
花朵、动物、阳光和...
only to find a world covered in flowers and animals and sunshine and...
还有树木、彩虹以及小兔子
And trees and rainbows and tiny little bunny rabbits.
闭上嘴巴划船吧
你这木头长舌男!
Shut up and row, you wooden windbag!
很快我就会拿到第二颗钻石了
Soon I will have the second diamond,
而那些进退不得的傻瓜
有的只有彼此...
and all those stranded simpletons will have is each other...
当作晚餐!
for dinner!
山姆,你毁了这一刻
Sam, you're ruining the moment.
对不起,长官
Sorry, sir.
那是银河(乳腺)吗,爱蜜楚?
Is that the Milky Way, Ermintrude?
布莱恩! 你不该问淑女
这么私人的问题!
Brian! You should never ask a lady anything so personal!
什么?
What?
星星是不是很美呀?
Aren't the stars beautiful?
好美
So beautiful.
你想不想成为他们其中之一呢?
Wouldn't you love to be one of them?
我愿不惜一切代价达成
I'd give anything.
你会成为一颗闪亮明星的
You'd make a wonderful star.
我敢说你说的没错
Oh, I dare say you're right.
如此晶莹剔透
So serene.
如此高高在上
So heavenly.
如此受人羡慕与崇拜
So admired and adored.
总是居高临下俯视着每个人
Always looking down on everyone.
没错!
Oooh, yes!
我们应该睡一下
We should get some sleep, man.
说真的,你光会想那件事吗?
Honestly,is that all you ever think about?
没错,只要我醒着的时候
Sure. Whenever I'm awake.
我睡不着
I can't sleep.
我太担心我的佛罗伦丝了
I'm too worried about my Florence.
她没有我好无助
She's so helpless without me.
她一定吓呆了
She must be petrified.
宠物? 炒炸?
Pets? Fried?
坏宿命
Bad karma.
没错,我安抚她
Exactly. I calm her down.
事实是,我愿为她做任何事
The truth is, I do everything for her.
没有我,她的生命会相当空虚
Her life would be quite empty without me there.
别烤金仓鼠,老弟
Whoa...Don't toast the hamsters, dude.
在可怕的雷雨交加期间
她坚持要我爬上床跟她一起睡...
During scary thunderstorms,she insists I climb into bed with her...
保护她
for her protection.
她喜欢抛网球
And she just loves to throw a tennis ball.
谁会去帮她捡回来
Who's always there to bring it back
好让她有再抛一次的乐趣呢?
so she can have the pleasure of throwing it again?
我告诉你,狄伦
I'm telling you, Dylan.
我敢打赌她真的很怀念那事
I bet she really misses that.
真的真的真的很怀念
Really, really, really missing that.
佛罗伦丝?
Florence?
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
"蓝天先生"
Mr Blue Sky
"艳阳高照"
Sun is shinin' in the sky
"万里无云"
There ain't a cloud in sight
"雨过天青"
It's stopped rainin'
"人人在嬉戏"
Everybody's in a play
"你不明白这是美丽的新日子吗?"
And don't you know
it's a beautiful new day
"嘿-嘿-嘿"
Hey-ey-ey
"沿着大街奔跑"
Runnin' down the avenue
"看看阳光多么闪耀灿烂"
See how the sun shines brightly
"在城市里"
In the city
"在曾经荒芜的街道上"
On the streets where once was pity
"蓝天先生今日居住在此"
Mr Blue Sky is living here today
"嘿-嘿-嘿"
Hey-ey-ey
"蓝天先生"
Mr Blue Sky
"请告诉我们为什么"
Please tell us why
"你必须躲藏了那么久"
"那么久"
You had to hide away for so long.So long
"我们哪里做错了呢?"
Where did we go wrong?
"蓝天先生,你做的对"
Mr Blue, you did it right
"但夜晚先生就快到来"
But soon comes Mr Night
"悄悄地笼罩大地
如今他的手正在你的肩上"
Creepin' over,Now his hand is on your shoulder
"算了,我会这样子记住你的"
Never mind,I'll remember you this way
"我会这样子记住你的"
I'll remember you this way
"蓝天先生"
Mr Blue Sky
"请告诉我们为什么"
Please tell us why
"你必须躲藏了那么久"
You had to hide away for so long
"那么久"
So long
"我们哪里做错了呢?"
Where did we go wrong?
嘿,热带风情!
Hey, man. Tropical vibes!
可是你看,上面有冰覆盖着
But look, there's ice up ahead.
-哪里?
-肯定有奇怪的事情发生
- Where?- Something strange is definitely afoot.
对,肯定是只大脚
Yeah, it's definitely a foot.
好的,各位,准备降落
OK, everybody, prepare to land.
应该不远了
Can't be far now.
绝对是这处地方
This is definitely the place.
进去吧
- Let's press on.- Ow!
等一下,长官
Hold up, sir.
我先,长官! 可能很危险
我具有第六感...
After me, sir. It could be dangerous,and I've got a sixth sense for...
集中精神在其它五感上吧
Try concentrating on the other five
不然你可能会人头不保
and you might not lose your head.
这里有什么呢?
Now, what do we have here?
啊哈!
Aha!
这整个地方机关重重
The whole place is booby-trapped.
那我们怎么办,老大?
So, what do we do now, boss?
降落喽!
Land ho!
谢天谢地! 我等不及...
Thank goodness! I can't wait
体会脚踏实地的感觉
to feel earth beneath my hooves.
知道怎么降落这个东西吗?
Any idea how we can land this thing?
他们还活着!
They're still alive!
不会吧!
Well, boil my busby!
无所谓,所有的笨机关
需要一群呆子试闯
No matter. All that booby traps require are a bunch of boobies.
先让他们清除机关
我们再尾随进入
We'll let them clear the way,then we can just stroll in.
来吧!
- Come on!- Oh!
再低一点,再低一点
Lower, lower.
空间很大! 再低一点
Loads of room! Lower.
到站...
Here comes a...
-...了!
-平坦安稳的...
- Stop!-...nice smooth...
...坠毁
...crash.
刚好来得及吃午餐
Just in time for lunch.
看样子你在菜单上了
And it looks like you're on the menu.
不知道齐贝在哪里
I wonder where Zeebad is.
我们必定追上他了
做的不错,火车!
We must have overtaken him.Nice one, Train!
这没什么,兔子
No worries, Rabbit.
在这等着,保持待命状态
Wait here and keep your pistons pumping.
我们可能需要火速逃离
We may need to make a quick getaway.
嘿,我们速去速回吧
Hey, let's make itreally quick and go now.
不知道这些符号表示什么
I wonder what these symbols mean.
可能相当于古代的欢迎物... 喔!
It's probably the ancient equivalent of a welcome mat... Oh!
哦,我怎么这样没礼貌?
Oh, where are my manners?
-女士优先
-不,你先请
- Ladies first.- No, after you.
老人优先,亲爱的
Age before beauty, dear.
看在老天份上,我去吧
Oh, for heaven's sake, I'll go.
表情别这么惊讶,爱蜜楚
Don't look so shell-shocked,Ermintrude.
我或许慢吞吞
不过还是可以带头的
I may be slow,but I can still take the lead.
跟着我的足迹走吧
Just follow my trail.
看看谁在开始长脊骨呀
Well, look who's beginning to grow a spine.
脊骨? 你说“脊骨”是啥意思?
Spine? What do you mean "spine"?
打架我可是都冲第一名唷!
I'm always the first into the fray!
那些懒惰虫
这里就我任何事都肯做!
Those lazy tykes. I'm the only one who does anything around here!
老是“布莱恩做这个,布莱恩做那个”
It's "Brian do this, Brian do that."
“是,长官! 不,长官!
满满三袋,长官”
"Yes, sir. No, sir. Three bags full, sir."
他们待我像奴隶一般!
They treat me like a slave!
真是耻辱
“我的糖呢?”
It's a disgrace. "Where's my sugar?"
“我的草呢?”
他们一定以为我好欺负
"Where's my grass?"They must think I'm a soft touch.
但我总是爬回去
But I always go crawling back.
快过来吧,都安全了
Well, come on, it's all clear.
我们走
Let's go.
从没想到我会这么说,不过...
好个蜗牛呀!
I never thought I'd say this but...what a snail!
好的,在这儿等
他们是这么吩咐的,等
OK, wait here. That's what they said.Wait.
我不喜欢这样
I-I don't like this.
I don't like this.
什么东西? 我要进入隧道
我是火车,我喜欢隧道
What's this? I'll go into the tunnel.I'm a train. I like tunnels.
我会在这里等,就是那样,对
I'll wait here, that's it, yeah.
我会等...
I'll wait just...
喂!
- Hey!- Who!
有人找到钻石吗?
Anyone find the diamonds?
哦,嘟狗
难道你不知道兔子有点神经质吗?
Oh, Doog, man. Don't you know rabbits are kind of jumpy?
我没看到任何线索呀
I don't see any clues.
我们一定找错地方了
We must be in the wrong place.
宝座...
享受我最后口香糖之最佳地方
Oooh, a throne - the perfect place to enjoy my last gobstopper.
太棒了,扶手按钮!
Oh, great, a recline button!
钻石!
The diamond!
好酷的炫光秀
Cool light show, man.
哈,美丽的雷射光
Hello, pretty lasers.
不!
No-ooo!
那是警报光束!
They're alarm beams!
得有人穿过去取钻石
Someone has to get through to the diamond.
-我毛太多了
-我会发抖
- Well, I'm too hairy.- I've got the shakes.
看在莫札特的份上,我来!
Oh, for the love of Mozart, I'll do it!
我受过芭蕾舞训练,你们知道的
I trained as a ballerina, you know.
我的天鹅湖乃众人津津乐道...
My Swan Lake was the talk of...
少说些有的没的,快救我们出去!
Stop milking the moment and get me out of here!
漂亮! 真是超...
Well done! That was bril...
不!
No-oooo!
我想没人懂得武功吧?
I don't suppose anyone knows anything about martial arts?
只是一些基本的,像是功夫
空手道、柔道、剑道、跆拳道
Just the basics of, like, kung fu, karate,judo, kendo, tae kwon do,
样样都会道,以及...太极拳
anything-you-can-do and...t'ai chi.
有附蛋炒饭吗?
Oooh!Do they come with egg fried rice?
狄伦...你能打倒他们吗?
Dylan...can you beat them up?
对不起,我不崇尚暴力
Sorry, I don't believe in violence.
自卫例外
Except in self-defence.
老天! 那才叫我所谓的振作起来
Oh, man! That's what I call pulling yourself together.
呀! 呀!
Ya! Ya!
-放马过来吧,老兄
-狄伦!
- Wa! Ta! Come on, man.- Dylan!
我不光有漂亮脸蛋而已!
I'm not just another pretty face!
精彩的团队合作
马上取走钻石离开吧
Good group effort. Now, let's grab the diamond and head off.
我是火车,我有汽笛
I'm a train, I have a whistle.
这底下好暗
幸好我有隧道照明,嘻嘻!
It's dark down here.Lucky I have tunnel vision, hee, hee!
超大引擎、合金轮子...
Big engine, alloy wheels...
我可绝对不想落到那付下场
You wouldn't want to be on the wrong end of that.
所以...
So...
传说中的英勇战士
已经来取钻石了!
The fearless warrior of legendhas come to claim the diamond!
不完全是
英勇战士今天没办法来
Erm, no actually, the fearless warrior couldn't make it today,
所以换我们代替
so we came instead.
我们回家途中会交给他的
Er, we'll drop it in to him on the way home.
听着,你到底要不要钻石?
Look, do you want the diamond or don't you?
如果你是在提议的话...是的,请!
Er, well, if you're offering...yes, please!
我想到个更好的主意
I've got a better idea.
我们扑上去吧!
Let's jump him!
冲啊...
Chaaaaaa...
只是想想而已啦
It was just a thought.
要不然就...溜之大吉!
How about...run away!
糟糕!
Oh, no!
救命呀!
He-He-Help!
救命!
Help!
应该是狗啃骨头
不是骨头啃狗!
Dogs are meant to eat bones,not the other way around!
脑筋转的真快,嘟狗
That was quick thinking, Dougal.
是啊,只要你保持镇静
Yeah, well, if you keep your cool
别像只无头苍蝇到处晃...
没时间聊天了
and don't run around like a headless chicken... No time for chitchat.
我们拿了钻石就离开吧
Let's grab that diamond and get out.
不见了!
It's gone!
一群傻瓜! 在找这个吗?
Fools! Looking for this?
你最近就是站不稳
You just can't get the staff these days.
现在,要告诉我第三颗钻石在哪吗?
Now, do you want to tell me where the third diamond is?
甭想
Nope.
反抗无益!
Resistance is futile!
你们不是伟大齐贝的对手!
You're no match for the great Zeebad!
骄者必败
Pride comes before a fall.
嘟狗! 现在!
Dougal! Now!
万岁!
那是见最后一面了
Hooray!That's the last we'll see of them.
他会丢脸丢死了!
That took him down a peg or ten!
对,只不过你刚刚冲掉了
一号钻石和二号钻石
Yeah, man, except you just flushedaway diamonds one and two.
那...我们现在要去哪?
So...where do we go now?
我们得尽快赶回旋转木马那里
We must get back to the Roundaboutas fast as we can.
我知道好比“祸害遗千年”
I know there's like,"no rest for the wicked",
不过我是好人
此刻我需要睡个午觉
but I'm one of the good guys and right now I need a siesta.
看!
Look!
声音! 我就知道他们会来救我
Voices! I knew they'd come to rescue me.
等等,也许应该由我去救他们
Hang on, maybe I'm supposed to be rescuing them.
嘿,听起来好熟悉
Hey, that sound's familiar.
典型的火车声
总是在绝望时出现
Typical train. Always turns up when you least expect it.
各位快点,走了
Come on, gang. In we go.
哦,不
Oh, no.
好,我们离开这儿吧
Right, now, let's get out of here.
开慢点,你令我的乳汁翻搅
Oh, do slow down,you're making my milk churn.
你在说笑吗?
我们慢得跟蜗牛似的!
Are you kidding?We're moving at a snail's pace!
慢得跟蜗牛刚好适合我
Snail's pace suits me just fine.
哦,爱蜜楚!
Oh, Ermintrude!
那是你说过最窝心的话
That's the sweetest thing you've ever said.
放松点,嘟狗
Relax, Doogie.
不久这整个疯狂之旅
将会抛到我们脑后
Soon this whole crazy trip will be behind us.
在我们后面!
Behind us!
-我就是这意思
-不! 在我们后面!
- That's what I said, man.- No! Behind us!
快一点! 再快一点!
Faster! Faster!
低头!
Duck!
我一直想当云霄飞车!
I always wanted to be a roller coaster!
哇,兄弟!
Whoa, dudes!
谈谈差点进鬼门关的经验吧
Talk about a near-death experience.
我想我看到隧道尽头有光芒
I thought I saw the light at the end of the tunnel.
这正是隧道尽头的光芒!
That is the light at the end of the tunnel!
我们就快脱险了!
We're going to be OK!
而齐贝依然困在神殿里!
And Zeebad's still trapped in the temple!
那么那是谁?
他的邪恶双胞胎齐贝德吗?
Then, like, who's that,his evil twin, Zeebadder?
我的第三颗钻石在哪里?
Where's my third diamond?
锅炉,现在别输掉!
Whoa! Furnace, don't fail me now!
大家抓稳了!
Brace yourself, everybody!
注意断轨!
Whoa! Mind the gap!
嘿!
Hey!
大鼻子来也!
Here comes big nose!
谁快想想办法!
Somebody do something!
嘿,这一定是某种反跳跃装置
Hey, this must be some kinda anti-spring device.
-这会教齐贝慢下来
-真的?
- This'll slow Zeebad down.- Really?
也可能是弹跳座椅
- Aaaagh!- Or it could be an ejector seat.
那究竟是啥声音?
What the devil was that?
发生什么事? 我为何瞎了?
What happened? Why am I blind?
我们到达旋转木马了吗?
Did we reach the Roundabout yet?
原来我们要往那里!
So that's where you're headed!
旋转木马!
The Roundabout!
在那里就可找到我的钻石了!
And that's where I'll find my diamond!
再见了,粘球!
So long, slimeball!
山姆,上去车顶除掉囚犯
Sam, get up on the roof and dispose of the prisoner.
除掉囚犯?
Dispose of a prisoner?
不能那么做,长官
那样违反日内瓦公约
Can't do that, sir. Geneva Convention.
你猜怎样? 我管它公不公约!
Guess what? I'm unconventional!
管它公不公约,哈哈哈!
Un-con-ventional. Ha, ha, ha!
斩断他的头!
Off with his head!
啊! 救命呀!
Aaaargh! He-eeelp!
布莱恩!
Brian!
-欢迎上车!
-爱蜜楚,你救了我!
- Welcome aboard!- Ermintrude, you saved me!
别想穿越我
你这花枝招展的开罐器!
Don't cross me,you tarted-up tin opener!
快一点,你这百合肝叛徒!
Faster, you lily-livered traitor!
我要抢到那颗钻石!
I want that diamond!
多加点煤炭!
More coal!
哦! 不!
Oh! No!
前面轨道合并!
Trouble dead ahead!
那是我的轨道!
That's my line!
这就是你们不让路的结果!
Now, this is what happens when you don't brush regularly!
长官! 压力...过高!
Sir! The pressure - it's too much!
我知道,我知道!
I know, I know!
有时候我觉得
我要大发神经了!
Sometimes I feel I'm going quite insane!
不,长官,是锅炉!
No, sir, it's the boiler!
是...
It's...
谢天谢地! 我们安全了!
Thank goodness! We're safe!
我称那爆炸为蒸汽烟火!
I call that letting off steam!
哇!
- Hurrah!- Whoa!
我能飞了!
I can fly-y-y!
不,我不能
No, I can't.
今天一天已经飞够了!
Oh, that's enough flying for one day!
我们得比齐贝早一步
赶到旋转木马
We've got to get to the Round about before Zeebad.
等等,齐贝并不知道
钻石在旋转木马那儿
Hang on, Zeebad doesn't know the diamond's at the Roundabout.
严格说来并不正确...
Erm... Well, that's not strictly true...
那时候,在火车上...
Back there, on the Train...
我一时糊涂就...
就脱口而出了
I-I was confused and it...it just slipped out.
布莱恩,老兄!
Brian, man!
话已覆水难收
Well there's no use crying over spilt milk.
你说的倒轻松
That's easy for you to say.
大家快点,上火车!
Come on, people. To the Train!
看样子火车已经停驶了
Whoa. Looks like this service has been cancelled.
-你不要紧吧?
-嗯
- Are you all right?- Yeah.
可能要误点了
Delays look likely.
我想我已拉了活塞
I think I've pulled a piston.
不,不会这样子的
Ow! Nope, it's not gonna happen.
可怜的小火车!
Oh, poor Trainy!
太阳快下山了
Oh, the sun's setting.
只好靠我们自己力量去办了
We'll just have to make it under our own steam.
暂别了,老弟
Goodbye for now, old buddy.
你能办到的
You can make it.
跟着我们的足迹走
Just follow our tracks.
别担心我
你们走吧,去找出钻石
Don't worry about me.You go on, find the diamond.
再想一想... 我怎么办?
On second thoughts... What about me?
烂机器!
Wretched machines!
我一定要赶到旋转木马,趁...
I must reach the Roundabout before...
长官!
Ooh, sir!
我需要医疗
Medic needed.
SOS,求救...
SOS. Mayday. Oooh...
我? 救你?
Me? Help you?
你这软弱无能的迪斯可娃娃!
You treacherou mollusc-sparing disco dolly!
你的职责到此结束
Your tour of duty is over.
你不能遗弃伤兵,长官
You can't leave an injured soldier, sir.
不能吗?
Can't I?
那就等着瞧吧
Just watch me.
等一下!
Wait!
回来!
Come back!
邪恶坏蛋...真够狠心的
Evil villains...can be so cruel.
我走不动了
I can't go on.
我们已经走好几个小时了
We've been walking for hours.
好冷...
It's so c-c-cold.
我手脚都没知觉了
I can't feel my limb.
可是佛罗伦丝...还有孩子们
But Florence...and the children.
如果我们不及早赶到
他们会冻成冰棒的
If we don't get there soon,they'll be frozen stiff.
哦,时间无情之手!
Oh, the cruel hands of time!
但要不是...要不是时间
一切会像是,瞬间发生
But if it... if it wasn't for time,everything would, like, happen at once.
等等,那是什么?
Wait. What's that?
脚印! 也许会带我们回村子里去
Footprints! Maybe they'll lead us back to the village.
可是,好像,有哪种古怪生物
会留下这些脚印?
But, like, what kinda freaky creatures would leave prints like these?
他们一定也是累毙了
They must be exhausted too.
其中一个好像用爬的爬过地面
One of them seems to be crawling along the ground.
我比较喜欢称为“滑过”
I prefer the term gliding.
不! 那是我们的脚印!
Oh, no! They're ours!
哦,不!
Oh, no!
不,不!
No, no!
就这样了,该好好睡上一觉了
Well, that's it, man.It's time for the big sleep.
我们尽力了
We did our best.
但我们的尽力还不够好...
But our best wasn't good enough. Oh...
哦,曲终人散
Oh, it's the final curtain.
不,千万不可睡着
No. We mustn't sleep.
太冷了
It's too cold.
我们千万不可...
We mustn't...
佛罗伦丝...
Florence...
嘟狗!
Doooougaaaal!
-嘟狗?
-佛罗伦丝! 你没事!
- Dougal?- Florence! You're OK!
比没事还要好
I'm more than OK.
我甜蜜无比
I'm swee-eeet.
但旋转木马呢?
But what about the Roundabout?
孩子们呢? 冻的缩成一团
The children? Huddled. Freezing.
别担心,嘟狗
Don't worry, Dougal.
你现在跟我在一起...
You're with me now...
在糖果天堂!
in sugar paradise!
你看,糖果要给我的小乖,嘟狗
Look. Sweets for my sweet Dougal.
喜欢吃多少就吃多少!
And you can eat as much as you like!
不,这样不对!我一定是疯了
N-No, this isn't right!I must be going nuts.
我得醒来,拯救佛罗伦丝
I have to wake up. Save Florence.
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
不!
No!
只是一场梦
It was just a dream.
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
Flore-eeeeence!
快醒醒!
Come on. Wake up!
醒醒! 醒醒!
Wake up! Wake up!
不行,我意识陷入高度恍惚状态
No way, man. I'm in a higher state
of unconsciousness.
天越来越亮了 我们却还完全迷失方向
It's getting light and we're still completely lost.
我不太确定我们是这样
I'm not so sure we are.
哇,真是严重的梦游
Whoa, that was some
serious sleepwalking.
看!
Look!
看,看,看!
Look, look, look!
快! 来看一下!看看那个!
Quick! Come and have a look!Look at that!
真的和我想的是一样吗?
Is that really what I think it is?
家?
Home?
诅咒!
Curses!
钻石一定在这里哪个地方!
The diamond
must be here somewhere!
齐贝!
Zeebad!
你!
You!
这旋转木马不够大容不下我们两个!
This roundabout ain't big enough for the both of us!
当我留下某人等死时就是指望对方死掉
When I leave someone for dead,I expect them to die.
你就不能乖乖死掉吗?
Can't you even do that right? Eh?
自从我离开旋转木马后还没做对过半样事
Oh, I haven't done anything right since I left the Roundabout.
现在是我重整旗鼓的时候了
Now it's time for me
to resume my post.
你? 你本来在旋转木马上面?
You? You were on the Roundabout?
对,我是
Yeah, I was.
阻挡住像你这种人
Guarding it from the likes of you.
哈! 瞧你这付模样!
Ha! Look at the state of you!
连颗水煮蛋都守不住了!
You couldn't guard a boiled egg!
我可能已受到损坏
Well, I might have taken a battering,
不过就像齐比迪跟我说的:
but it's like Zebedee told me:
心里想什么才重要!
it's what's inside that counts!
冲呀!
Chaaaaarge!
钻石!
The diamond!
齐比迪,你这狡猾的家伙
Oooh, Zebedee, you cunning swine.
再想一下,我留你自生自灭
差点就抛弃了钻石
And to think, I nearly abandoned it when I left you to die.
真是讽刺!
Ooh, the irony!
现在,该来天寒地冻了!
Now, time for the big chill!
这不可能是我们的村子
This can't be our village.
我一样都不认得了
I don't recognise a thing.
对,好像,也许我们转错弯了,嘟狗
Yeah, like, maybe we took a wrong turn, Doog.
不,不,绝对是这里
No, no, this is definitely it.
只要我们经过这个白色东东
If we go past this white thingy
再经过这个白色的...
and by this white bit...
转角过去应该就是...
just round the corner should be the...
哦,不!
Oh, no!
哈哈哈!
Ha, ha, ha!
齐贝!
Zeebad!
完美极了!
Ah, perfect!
你们刚好赶上最后一幕
You've arrived just in time for the finale.
再见了,阳光!
So long, sunshine!
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
哦,佛罗伦丝!
Oh, Florence!
不,不,不,不,不!
Oh, no, no, no, no, no!
全是我的错
This is all my fault.
如果我没那么贪吃、愚蠢
If only I hadn't been so greedy and stupid.
那么再会了,狄伦
再见,亲爱的布莱恩
Farewell, then, Dylan.Goodbye, dear Brian.
爱蜜楚,在我们结冻之前
Er...Ermintrude, before we freeze,
有件事我一直想告诉你...
there's something I've been t-trying to t-tell you...
这家伙严重扰乱我的宿命!
This guy is seriously messing with my karma!
吃这个吧
你这弹跳的恶作剧盒玩具!
Eat this,you jumped-up jack-in-the-box! Ya!
你就是不明白你被打败了,对不对?
Ooof! You just don't know when you're beaten, do you?
吃颗寒气丸吧,兔子!
Take a chill pill, rabbit!
等一下,就是那样!
Wait a minute. That's it!
爱蜜楚,唱歌!
能唱多大声就唱多大声!
Ermintrude, sing!Sing as loud as you can!
我不习惯在这种情况下演唱!
I'm not used to working under these conditions!
嘟狗可能想到了什么法子
Dougal might be onto something.
对! 爱蜜楚! 快唱!
Yes! Ermintrude! Sing!
我还没暖嗓呢!
I haven't even warmed up!
爱蜜楚! 快唱!
Ermintrude! Sing!
好啦
Fine.
那是什么讨厌的噪音啊?
What is that abominable noise?
装填弹药!
Shell loaded!
吃这招吧!
Take this!
快逃!
Run!
准备好没? 瞄准,发射!
Ready? Aim. Fire!
漂亮!
Well done!
狄伦,往你那边去了!
Dylan, it's coming your way!
哇,这一撞可不轻!
Whoa, that was some hit!
哇! 棒透了!
Whoa! Psy-che-delic!
我来挥棒
I got it, man.
不!
No!
给我! 给我!
Over to me! Over to me!
不! 是我的! 我的! 哈哈!
No! It's mine! Mine! Ha, ha!
二比零!
Two-nil!
比赛还没结束呢
The game's not over yet.
接的好,齐贝!
Oooh, nice catch, Zeebad!
现在来抢最后的...
Now let's get the final...
钻石!
diamond!
敢碰它你就死定了
Touch it and you're toast.
你吓不倒我!
你只是个蓝色大混蛋
You don't scare me!You're just a big, blue bully.
现在局势已逆转
Now the tables have turned
我们只需要
把最后这颗钻石放回...
and all we need do is put this last diamond back on...
全垒打出击!
Here comes a home run!
休想!
Not again!
胜利!
Victory!
就差这么一点...
So close and yet so...
太好了!
far out!
对一群呆子动物而言
做的还不错!
Nice try - for a bunch of dumb animals!
不过动物园关闭时间到了
But now it's closing time at the zoo.
用我们的秘密武器就不会
齐比迪的魔法盒!
Not with our secret weapon:Zebedee's magic box!
没有用!
- Huh?
- Ya!
现在齐比迪的玩具
也帮不了你们了
It d-doesn't work. Aw!
我回来了! 呀呼!
Bounce back from that, Slinky!Woo-hoo!
火车! 我就知道你办的到!
Train! I knew you'd make it!
-照时刻表行驶
-钻石!
- Bang on schedule.- The diamond!
我去拿
I'll get it.
我害大家淌这趟浑水
我要救大家出来
I got us into this mess and I'll get us out.
去呀,嘟狗
Go on, Dougal.
不!
No-ooo-ooo!
哈哈哈!
Mm-mm! Ha, ha, ha!
成功了! 成功了!
We did it! We did it!
快点!
Come on!
干的好!
Well done!
没什么能像歌剧一样能够破冰
There's nothing like opera
for breaking the ice.
绿茵映眼帘!甜美苍翠的绿草!
I can see grass, man!Sweet, green grass!
可是佛罗伦丝人呢?
But where's Florence?
佛罗伦丝?
Florence?
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
佛罗伦丝,能听见我吗?
Florence, can you hear me?
拜你醒来
Please wake up.
拜你醒来,别离开我
Please wake up. Don't leave me.
没有你,这世界就毫无意义了!
This world means nothing without you!
我很遗憾,老弟
Sorry, old buddy.
不,不会的...
No, it can't...
她不会的...
She can't...
佛罗伦丝!
Florence!
我可爱的佛罗伦丝!
My lovely Florence!
她动了!
She moved!
她还活着!
She's alive!
哦,佛罗伦丝!
我以为我永远失去你了!
Oh, Florence!I thought I'd lost you forever!
我也以为我失去你了,嘟狗
And I thought I'd lost you too, Dougal.
但你救了我的命
But you saved my life.
还有大家的命
And everyone else's.
别说了
Oh, stop it.
任何超级英雄狗都会这么做的
It's what any incredibly heroic dog would do.
那么你不想要一份...
So you don't want a...
小小的奖赏吗?
little reward?
不用,我已经学乖了
Oh, no. I've learnt my lesson.
我再也不跟棒棒糖扯上关系了
I'm not having anything more to do with lollipops.
或口香糖
Or gobstoppers.
或太妃糖
Or toffees.
等一下,齐比迪到哪去了?
But wait, where's Zebedee?
齐比迪!
Zebedee!
好极了,我的朋友们
我一直明白你们能办到!
Bravo, my friends.I always knew you could do it!
但我们以为你死了!
But we thought you were dead!
死了? 胡说,嘟狗!
Dead? Nonsense, Dougal!
人人都知道冬天过后
就是春天!
Everyone knows that after winter it's time for spring!
大家快点来坐旋转木马吧!
Come on, everyone.To the Roundabout!
哦,不!
Oh, no!
为什么不动?
How come it's not moving?
好像卡住了
It's like stuck, man.
旋转木马怎么了?
What's wrong with the Roundabout?
齐比迪?
Zebedee?
你们不记得了吗?
Don't you remember?
旋转木马还缺了一样东西
The Roundabout's still missing something.
或者该说...缺了一个人
Or should I say... someone?
山姆?
Sam?
但那是齐贝的心腹!
But that's Zeebad's henchman!
他折磨我!
He tortured me!
别太苛责他
Don't be too hard on him.
山姆也是齐贝
疯狂魔法下的受害者
Sam too was a victim of Zeebad's maniacal magic.
该回去你原来的地方了,山姆
It's time for you to return where you belong, Sam.
"蜜糖"
Sugar
"甜心啊甜心"
Ah, honey, honey
"你是我的糖果女孩"
You are my candy girl
"你教我想要你..."
And you got me wanting you...
"蜜糖呀蜜糖..."
Ah, sugar, sugar...
外型不错唷!
Nice shade of moose!
鹿蹄也很适合!
With matching hooves!
嘟狗?
- Dougal?- Huh?
嘟狗? 嘟狗?
Dougal? Dougal?
"鸟和蜂对我齐声歌唱"
The birds and the bees are all singin' to me
"告诉我你所看见的"
Tell me what you see
"美丽天空总是令人心旷神怡"
The beautiful sky always makin' us happy
"会是一趟美妙之旅..."
It's gonna be a wonderful trip...
嘟狗!
- Dougal!- Erm...
"你与我一起..."
Together you and me...
糖,糖,糖呀!
Sugar, sugar, sugar!
糖!
Sugar!
"我在高空中遨游"
I'm riding high up in the sky
"你没看见吗?"
Can you see?
"阳光灿烂明媚"
The sun is shinin'
"美好时光来临"
These are good times
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"所有朋友聚在一起"
All friends together now
"来徜徉漫游吧"
Come and take a trip
"因为它多美好"
Cos it's all right
"加入欢乐行列"
So join in with the fun
"骑乘才刚开始"
The ride has just begun
"我们不要下去"
We're never comin' down
"我们正转呀转"
We're spinnin' round and round
"乘着神奇的旋转木马"
On the Magic Roundabout
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"展开冒险旅程,我们要去找你了"
Off on an adventure,we're comin' to getcha
"不管会在何方"
Wherever that may be
"都不会让任何事来令你沮丧"
Won't let anything come here and upset you
"我要释放你"
I'm gonna set you free
"不管沿途会发生什么事
都会安然无恙"
Whatever happens along the way,it's gonna be fine
"哦,是的"
Oh, yeah
"将忧虑抛诸脑后"
Leave our worries behind
"我喜爱这种感觉"
I love this feeling
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"所有朋友聚在一起"
All friends together now
"来徜徉漫游吧,因为它多美好..."
Come and take a trip cos it's all right...
哦,诅咒!
Oh, curses!
又被关起来了!
Imprisoned once more!
至少很冷
Ah, well, at least it's cold.
双重诅咒!
Double curses!
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"我在高空中遨游"
I'm flying high up in the sky
"你没看见吗?"
Can you see?
"阳光灿烂明媚"
The sun is shinin'
"美好时光来临"
These are good times
"哦!"
Whoo!
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"所有朋友聚在一起"
All friends together now
"来徜徉漫游吧"
Come and take a trip
"因为它多美好"
Cos it's all right
"加入欢乐行列"
So join in with the fun
"骑乘才刚开始"
The ride has just begun
"我们不要下去"
We're never comin' down
"我们正转呀转"
We're spinnin' round and round
"神奇的旋转木马"
The Magic Roundabout
"所有朋友聚在一起"
All friends together now
"来徜徉漫游吧"
Come and take a trip
"因为它多美好"
Cos it's all right
"加入欢乐行列..."
So join in with the fun...
哦...你还在
Oh... Oh, you're still there.
我没告诉你吗?
Didn't I tell you?
该睡觉了!
Time for bed!